
   
      
         
            Letter #20 from Robert Graves to William Graves (at Oundle School) November 8, 1957
         
         
            Publication Information
         
         
            Information about the source
         
      
   
   
      
          8th Feb Dear William,

         So glad to get your letter. We now have a microphone for the tape recorder and it wrks very well so we can do some 
            recordings this summer. Just back from Palma where we went for Juanito of the Fabrica's wedding. As 
            the familythefamily has stolen so much from us we had to give them a decent wedding 
            present so bought them some silver candlesticks - as they are living in Palma it will
            remind them of Deya. There has still been no proper rain this winter, so you can imagine what the light is like. The wedding
            
               L
               t
            ook place at the church of San Francisco and the reception was in the Hotel
            Ensanche - the wedding was very nice but not the reception - too many people and the food was not specially good and 
            they played worn out gramophone records, or sounded like it.

         I have just been in Madrid - I went back with Lucia to stay a few days with her and Stella while she took
            the Oxford exam at the British institute. I don't think she will have got in - it depends on how much credit they give her for her A-levels, (which
            they don't insist on at Oxford) and school report etc.

         
            
               XX XX S**************At this point, Tomas wants to write a few words -

               dearWilliam. . xx ... xx. ..............................

               I am here going to stop 9(I am going all wrong)

               To continue: Had a great time in Madrid as their flat is very nice - they've made it nice - but didn't do much except provide meals
                  etc for Lucia and visited Mary once and also Stella's mad school. On the Sunday we took Jasperout for the day, he really

               ......love.....Thomas.....graves
            
         

         is a marvellous boy and loves going out in the Morris. He goes to Stella's school some mornings. Another person I saw in Madrid was Ita's mother,
            Laura, who is staying there with her sisters. Ita is working for Dan now, as a Rentavilla courier. Maria Elena is in New York - in case you want to
            look her up on your way through her tel. no in UNIVERSITY 6 -2746 and her name is Mrs Andre Schiffrin.

         So glad you will be black in June. By the way Micky Rosenstingl has a Volkswagen now and considers you his 'blood brother' so you had better go for
            a Morris!

         The Dinosaur book has not arrived yet, but Tomas is anxiously awaiting it. We gave him carpentry things for his birthday as he got a taste for it in
            Fornalutx where he used to go and work for a Soller carpenter on Saturdays.

         Have written again to the Swiss bank about the October money which seems to have vanished into thin air. It has gone out of our account and if it
            hasn't gone into yours it's for them to find out where it has gone, Swiss or not.

         I'll leave the rest of the page for Father, in case he wants to add anything. - lots of love from us all.

         RG: You'll be very pleased with Tomas: he's so bright & well informed and sensible these days. Never swam, before, most of January and now in
            February: and it's pleasure not bravado. Freud: yes, it is interesting to know what he is all about so that you can laugh at it all. In America he's
            still current. In England he's exploded (among top people at least) and gradually vanishing. It was a fad like the 18th century habit of putting
            cows in bedrooms so that women could be healed by their sweet breaths. To be psycho-analyzed is to have Freud planted in you: and you yourself die.
            The White Goddess is a crazy book. She represents the unpredictable natural woman, wholly uninhibited by male honour or conscience or intellect but
            with extraordinary (call them magical) powers: without whom this world would be a dull world indeed. The poet is her intermediary. Something like
            that. A muse is a woman who has these powers; almost always they destroy her in the end, the world being what it is. Yes: one can stop time
            poetically: or perform any common miracle if it is really necessary. But not experimentally or for display. Idries should be here in a month's time
            to write his Sufi book: he's made fantastic discoveries of the secret influence of Sufi thought in the English Middle Ages: proof in exact chapter
            and verse, for pages and pages. (That rhymes so it must be true!).

         Love, Father.
      
   
